import type { MCQ } from '../../../types'

export const mcqSet12: MCQ[] = [
  {
    "id": 111,
    "question": "In Scala, what does the term 'covariance' refer to?",
    "options": [
      "The ability to define methods that can accept multiple argument types",
      "The property of a type parameter indicating that it can vary in the same direction as its container type",
      "The process of converting one data type to another implicitly",
      "The feature allowing classes to inherit from multiple parent classes"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 112,
    "question": "What is the main function of the ResourceManager in Hadoop YARN (Yet Another Resource Negotiator)?",
    "options": [
      "To manage and monitor Hadoop cluster nodes",
      "To manage storage resources within the Hadoop Distributed File System (HDFS)",
      "To manage and allocate computing resources (CPU, memory) across applications in the cluster",
      "To schedule and execute MapReduce jobs on the Hadoop cluster"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 113,
    "question": "In which scenario would Apache Storm be most suitable?",
    "options": [
      "Real-time processing of social media data for sentiment analysis",
      "Batch processing of historical sales data for monthly reports",
      "Static analysis of log files for system performance monitoring",
      "Indexing and searching large volumes of text documents"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 114,
    "question": "Which of the following steps is NOT typically part of the process of creating a data product?",
    "options": [
      "Data collection and preprocessing",
      "Model training and evaluation",
      "Deployment and monitoring",
      "Business requirements analysis"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 115,
    "question": "What fundamental service does GitHub primarily offer to software developers?",
    "options": [
      "A cloud-based platform for storing, managing, and sharing code repositories using Git version control",
      "A suite of project management tools tailored for software development teams",
      "A communication platform for developers to collaborate and discuss coding projects",
      "A scalable cloud storage solution optimized for hosting large datasets"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 116,
    "question": "Which feature of MongoDB makes it suitable for real-time analytics and data science applications?",
    "options": [
      "ACID transactions for ensuring data consistency and integrity",
      "Sharding and replication for horizontal scalability and high availability",
      "GridFS for storing and retrieving large files, such as images and videos",
      "Aggregation framework for performing complex data analysis and aggregations"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 117,
    "question": "Which feature of Teradata makes it suitable for handling large-scale data analytics tasks?",
    "options": [
      "Teradata's integration with Apache Hadoop for distributed processing",
      "Teradata's support for real-time data streaming and event processing",
      "Teradata's in-memory processing capabilities for high-speed analytics",
      "Teradata's ability to automatically optimize and tune database queries"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 118,
    "question": "What distinguishes reasoning AI from other AI approaches?",
    "options": [
      "Reasoning AI primarily focuses on pattern recognition and classification tasks",
      "Reasoning AI relies on predefined rules and logic to make decisions and draw conclusions",
      "Reasoning AI emphasizes deep learning techniques for feature extraction and representation",
      "Reasoning AI is specialized in natural language processing and understanding"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 119,
    "question": "What role does MATLAB play in computational tasks?",
    "options": [
      "It serves as a platform for data analysis and visualization",
      "It functions as a database management system",
      "It acts as a web development tool",
      "It facilitates artificial intelligence research"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 120,
    "question": "What is the typical source of data for business intelligence compared to data science?",
    "options": [
      "Business intelligence relies on structured data stored in relational databases, while data science works with both structured and unstructured data from various sources",
      "Business intelligence primarily uses unstructured data from social media platforms, while data science relies on structured data from transactional databases",
      "Business intelligence and data science both use structured data from spreadsheets and CSV files",
      "Business intelligence and data science both rely on collecting data through online surveys and questionnaires"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": 0
  }
]
